<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Li Lejia's Blog</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2016-05-18T03:00:41+08:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Li Lejia</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>leelejia@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recent introspection]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/introspection/" />
  <id>/introspection</id>
  <updated>2016-05-10T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-05-18T00:00:00+08:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Li Lejia</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>leelejia@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;If a-year-younger-me ask the now-me for advices, I will share some points with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First of all, do all things proactively instead of reactively (This is what Zuckburg shared to F8ers in CEO weekly Q&amp;amp;A). When it comes to your career, what you have done is the only criteria of your own ability, at least it’s the only thing you can show to your leader and your colleague your smartness and effort. Your mom or you spouse may know you are a great guy, but they do not. You should come out and do things to prove it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;However, one man can achieve few things during limited time. So you need a team. So you recruit a team. Recruit is actually quite not that hard because it’s almost a linear complicity. The problem is what things each team member will do based on what exact common goal. That problem is called management. From now on, you should realize that normally what yourself can achieve anything proves little, what you lead a whole team achieve one big goal talks. From now on, you should not trying to organize your own time but also others’. You have to prove that everybody else are doing things proactively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After all, I am still a young boy on management. It’s all about goal, time and people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be responsible to your leader and be responsible to your teammates. Sometimes the form is more important.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sleep earlier and get up earlier. You can hardly get up at 7 am. while you slept at 2 am.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a good leader. A experienced leader is a mentor and advisor. Or it will really really suck, trust me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/introspection/&quot;&gt;Recent introspection&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Li Lejia at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Li Lejia's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World Again]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/hello-world-again/" />
  <id>/hello-world-again</id>
  <updated>2016-5-8T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-05-08T00:00:00+08:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Li Lejia</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>leelejia@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;hello-world-again&quot;&gt;Hello world again.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;前一段时间 lejia.li 的域名过期了，然而续费的时候竟然没有续费成功，不过几个月以后又被我注册成功。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;因为之前各种乱七八糟的原因，博客竟然断了快两年，实在是不应该（好吧，当真正又想用才开始弄）。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;之前的博客用 Jekyll 生成的，md 源文件在之前的电脑里不知道还找不找得到，如果找得到有可能还能恢复回来，不过之前写的东西倒是都很浅，之后写的东西干货还是多一点。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;自从来了 Lesports 干起了所谓的管理，差不多已经完全放下了代码的工作。Honestly, 我是个很靠外部激励而推进的人，自己内在的推动力很难坚持很久，然而管理工作实际上是一个成就感回馈地很慢的一个工作，再加之其实并没有一个 mentor 的角色来帮助我去适应，导致我在这方面适应地很糟糕。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;最近又由于乱七八糟的很多原因，开始了写美颜的算法，知识上的收获必定是有，然而更大的是操作方法上的回归，我发现我已经很久没有去立体地拆分一个问题、解决一个问题了，而如此一步一步地思考问题、解决问题又终于让我回到了一些向上的正轨。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我竟然又开始了走路吃饭的时候也开始思考问题了，that’s original me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;两次上厕所，一次买咖啡路上，让我想到了三个问题的解决办法。Bingo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/hello-world-again/&quot;&gt;Hello World Again&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Li Lejia at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Li Lejia's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 08, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
